# **BSc GRASIELE ROMANZINI BEZERRA**

#### **MASTER STUDENT**

Brazilian Center for Research in Physics, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

✓ bezerragrasiele@gmail.com

# PROFILE \_\_\_\_\_

Grasiele Romanzini Bezerra is curriently cursing a full time master degree at Brazilian Center for Research in Physics (CBPF), Brazil, and she holds a bachelor degree in Physics (2020) from Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul (UFRGS), Brazil. Besides having an advanced knowledge in data science and excellent computational skills, she also has 5 years experience in analyse scientific and social data using a varied range of programming languages, such as python, R and C. Most of her research is focused on astrophysics, cosmology and modified gravity, moreover she also has experience in using sciencemetry to understand and explain social behaviours.

## EDUCATION \_

Master in Cosmology: Brazilian Center for Research in Physics (CBPF), Rio de Janeiro, Brazil (In progress).

BSc in Physics, Physics Institute, Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil (2020).

# RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

#### Master Student

## Brazilian Center for Research in Physics, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

 Project: Galaxy Dynamics and Modified Gravity from Einstein Rings and Velocity Dispersion

Aug 2021 - Present

- Supervisor: Dr. Martin Makler
- Co-Supervisor: Dr. Cristina Furlanetto

#### Scientific Initiation

Physics Institute, Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul, Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil

 Project: Testing the Parameterized Post-Newtonian Gravity with Strong Gravi Jan 2019 - Feb 2020 tational Lensing

- Advisor: Dr. Cristina Furlanetto
- Analyse data of 103 lensing galaxies from 4 different surveys

# Internship

Physics Institute, Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul, Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil

• Project: Gender Diversity in Science

Jun 2015 - Jul 2019

- Advisor: Dr. Marcia C. B. Barbosa
- Statistical analyses of gender diversity using data of 5 thousand Brazilian scientist

# PUBLICATIONS \_\_\_\_

Bezerra, Grasiele Romanzini, Daniela Lazzaro, Aruquia Peixoto, Maria Margaret Lopes, C Andrade, H. J. N. Lopes, and Márcia C. Barbosa (2019). "Female Researchers in Science in Brazil: the Scissors Effect". In: La Brecha de Género en Matemática, Computación y Ciencias Naturales. Edited by Lilia Meza Montes and Silvina Ponce Dawson. Mexican Physic Society, pages 55-67.

Ferrari, Nathália C, Raquel Martell, Daniela H Okido, Grasiele Romanzini, Viviane Magnan, Márcia C Barbosa, and Carolina Brito (2018). "Geographic and gender diversity in the Brazilian Academy of Sciences". In: Anais da Academia Brasileira de Ciências 90.2, pages 2543-2552.

**Bezerra, Grasiele** and Marcia C Barbosa (2016). "Mulheres na física no brasil". In: *SBF Sociedade Brasileira de Física – 50 anos – 1966 – 2016 (Book of 50 years of the Brazilian physic society)*. Edited by Alicia Ivanissevich and Cássio Leite Vieira. Brazilian Physic Society, pages 132–135.

### EVENTS \_\_\_

Oral Presentation - Testing Gravity with Einstein Rings and Velocity Dispersion: II Workshop on Lensing by Galaxies and Clusters, AUG 2022.

Flash Talk - Galaxy Dynamics and Modified Gravity from Velocity Dispersion in E-Rings Systems: Cosmology from Home 2022, JUL 2022.

Oral Presentation - Testing the Parameterized Post-Newtonian Gravity with Strong Gravitational Lensing: First Workshop on Lensing by Galaxies and Clusters, Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul, Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil. Oct 2019.

Poster Presentation - Geographic and Gender Diversity in the Brazilian Academy of Sciences: IX Workshop in Complexity of Water and Other Liquids, Federal University of Pelotas, UFPel, Pelotas, RS, Brazil. Nov 2018.

**Poster Presentation - Women in Physics in Brazil:** VII Workshop in Complexity of Water, Other Liquids and Science Education, Federal University of Santa Catarina, Ararangua, SC, Brazil. Nov 2016.

**Poster Presentation - Women in Physics:** VI Workshop on Complexity of Water and other Liquids, Federal University of Santa Catarina, Ararangua, SC, Brazil. Nov 2015.

# SCHOOLS \_\_\_\_\_

Summer School: Astroinformatics II, Center for Astrostatistics, The Pennsylvania State University, USA. Jun 2022

**Summer School:** Statistics for Astronomers XVII, Center for Astrostatistics, The Pennsylvania State University, USA. Jun 2022

Winter school: XIII CBPF's winter school, Brazilian Center for Research in Physics (CBPF), Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. December Aug 2021.

Winter School: Astrophysical Winter 2019, Center for Astrophysics and Cosmology of the UFES, Castelo, ES, Brazil. Aug 2019.

# PROFESSIONAL TRAINING \_\_\_\_\_

Jul 2021 - Professional Certificate in Data Science, Harvard.

Jun 2021 - Course - Data Visualization and Communication with Tableau, Duke University.

Mar 2021 - Course - Privacy Law and Data Protection, University of Pennsylvania.

Aug 2020 - Course - Data-driven Astronomy, The University of Sydney.

Feb 2020 - Course - Introduction to Astronomy, Federal Institute Farroupilha.

grasiele R. Bezerra